<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title> - Articles</title>
    <description>Think like a native, Speak like a native.</description>
    <link>
    </link>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>IELTS Speaking Tip 1</title>
        
          <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;ielts-speaking-tip-1&quot;&gt;IELTS SPEAKING TIP #1&lt;/h1&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 16:56:28 +0330</pubDate>
        <link>
        /blog/ielts-speaking-tip-1</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/ielts-speaking-tip-1</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Toastmasters</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Our Toastmasters Classes are starting from next Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 03:30:00 +0330</pubDate>
        <link>
        /classes/toastmasters</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/classes/toastmasters</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Writing Essay (Part 2)</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;When facing a writing task, there are five possible forms of questions. We’ll help you have an idea of what to do with the question. These are the five types:
Opinion Essay Questions
 Discussion Essay Questions
Solution Essay Questions
Direct Questions Essay Titles
Advantage/ Disadvantage Essay Question
Each of them will be explained one by one in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 13:48:00 +0330</pubDate>
        <link>
        /blog/IELTS-Essay-2</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/IELTS-Essay-2</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Writing Essay</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;For writing a good essay, there are many steps you need to take. But before taking those steps you need to be informed on the topics. The most frequent topics are:
Art&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 13:48:00 +0330</pubDate>
        <link>
        /blog/IELTS-Essay</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/IELTS-Essay</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>EPT/MSRT Preparation Course</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;EPT (English Proficiency Test) is launched by Islamic Azad University (IAU) for PhD test takers to examine their proficiency in English language. The exam including 25 questions on vocabulary, 40 questions on grammatical points and 35 questions on comprehensive reading. The exam doesn’t have negative scores and exam pass score is 50% of total score.
Research and development center of IAU noted following text books as reference for this exam:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 14:48:00 +0430</pubDate>
        <link>
        /classes/EPT-MSRT</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/classes/EPT-MSRT</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Business English Course</title>
        
          <description>BEC is a well-recognized international certificate that launched by Cambridge English. The aim of test is to examine English Skills in a business context.
There are three levels of BEC:
1- BEC Preliminary (B1): to understand routine letters, make notes, follow basic presentations and advise clients on simple matters. (Prerequisite: Intermediate level of Professional trade language Course)
2- BEC Vantage (B2): to understand the general meaning of reports, write non-routine letters and present arguments. (Prerequisite: Upper-Intermediate level of Professional trade language Course)
3- BEC Higher (C1): to deal with unpredictable questions, argue a business case and write business reports. (Prerequisite: Advanced level of Professional trade language Course)
This is a lifetime certificate that can boost your opportunities in international corporations. More corporates and Businesses require their employees to hold BEC certificate before they are recruited. Sony, Shell, Vodafone, Bayer, BMW, AUDI, HSBC, Adidas are only a few companies to mention in growing list of corporates that require their employees to hold BEC certificate.
Binesh Afza Language Institute’s Professional Trade Language Course can help not only professional business man/woman handling their challenging situations in business but also can help you prepare for BEC Exam. Students and Professors of International Trading Courses, Organization legal department representatives, business owners and people who are offering business advice to international corporates can be benefited greatly from this course.
You are expected to have an intermediate level of knowledge in English language skills before Professional Trade Language Course at Binesh Afza Language Institute. This course will enable you to professionally handle:</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 13:30:00 +0430</pubDate>
        <link>
        /classes/bec</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/classes/bec</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>IELTS/TOEFL/PTE</title>
        
          <description>Beyond conventional test prep programs
Binesh Afza’s preparation class courses focus on enabling students to understand the content in-depth rather than a download of voluminous basic knowledge interspersed with tricks. Our difference lies in the fact that we care about the students’ literacy as well. Instead of parroting the empty, low-scoring fixed expressions and mechanical constructs, we help you brainstorm and develop your own ideas in your own genuine style. The course also includes a review of grammar and free discussion sessions.
Last but not least, fifty percent of the tuition is refundable if the course fails to help you achieve the band score you need.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 09:30:00 +0430</pubDate>
        <link>
        /classes/IELTS-TOEFL-PTE</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/classes/IELTS-TOEFL-PTE</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Teaching Training Course</title>
        
          <description>TTC prepare students with advanced English Skills for teaching adults or children. Students can choose to teach either Adult Learner (AL) or Young Learner (YL) based on their interest in handling different type of challenges they face for each group.
Binesh Afza Language Institute will issue worldwide recognized TTC certificate under International Labor Organization (ILO) license. This certificate is valid in 187 countries worldwide including but not limited to USA, England, Australia, Canada and most of European countries. TTC certificate can be verified by your potential employer through your TTC certificate international code and the certificate doesn’t need to be translated.
TTC Course will help students to identify: </description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 08:30:00 +0430</pubDate>
        <link>
        /classes/ttc</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/classes/ttc</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>English Podcast</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey! Welcome to Ghost, it’s great to have you :)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 14:30:00 +0430</pubDate>
        <link>
        /news/welcome</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/welcome</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
