<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title> - Articles</title>
    <description>Learn English Easily With Us</description>
    <link>
    </link>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Game Day</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;12313&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 22:24:00 +0330</pubDate>
        <link>
        /news/game-day</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/game-day</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Toastmasters</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Our Toastmasters Classes are starting from next Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 03:30:00 +0330</pubDate>
        <link>
        /classes/toastmasters</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/classes/toastmasters</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Writing Essay (Part 2)</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;When facing a writing task, there are five possible forms of questions. We’ll help you have an idea of what to do with the question. These are the five types:
Opinion Essay Questions
 Discussion Essay Questions
Solution Essay Questions
Direct Questions Essay Titles
Advantage/ Disadvantage Essay Question
Each of them will be explained one by one in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 13:48:00 +0330</pubDate>
        <link>
        /blog/IELTS-Essay-2</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/IELTS-Essay-2</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Writing Essay</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;For writing a good essay, there are many steps you need to take. But before taking those steps you need to be informed on the topics. The most frequent topics are:
Art&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 13:48:00 +0330</pubDate>
        <link>
        /blog/IELTS-Essay</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/IELTS-Essay</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>EPT/MSRT Preparation Course</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;EPT (English Proficiency Test) is launched by Islamic Azad University (IAU) for PhD test takers to examine their proficiency in English language. The exam including 25 questions on vocabulary, 40 questions on grammatical points and 35 questions on comprehensive reading. The exam doesn’t have negative scores and exam pass score is 50% of total score.
Research and development center of IAU noted following text books as reference for this exam:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 14:48:00 +0430</pubDate>
        <link>
        /classes/EPT-MSRT</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/classes/EPT-MSRT</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Business English Course</title>
        
          <description>BEC is a well-recognized international certificate that launched by Cambridge English. The aim of test is to examine English Skills in a business context.
There are three levels of BEC:
1- BEC Preliminary (B1): to understand routine letters, make notes, follow basic presentations and advise clients on simple matters. (Prerequisite: Intermediate level of Professional trade language Course)
2- BEC Vantage (B2): to understand the general meaning of reports, write non-routine letters and present arguments. (Prerequisite: Upper-Intermediate level of Professional trade language Course)
3- BEC Higher (C1): to deal with unpredictable questions, argue a business case and write business reports. (Prerequisite: Advanced level of Professional trade language Course)
This is a lifetime certificate that can boost your opportunities in international corporations. More corporates and Businesses require their employees to hold BEC certificate before they are recruited. Sony, Shell, Vodafone, Bayer, BMW, AUDI, HSBC, Adidas are only a few companies to mention in growing list of corporates that require their employees to hold BEC certificate.
Binesh Afza Language Institute’s Professional Trade Language Course can help not only professional business man/woman handling their challenging situations in business but also can help you prepare for BEC Exam. Students and Professors of International Trading Courses, Organization legal department representatives, business owners and people who are offering business advice to international corporates can be benefited greatly from this course.
You are expected to have an intermediate level of knowledge in English language skills before Professional Trade Language Course at Binesh Afza Language Institute. This course will enable you to professionally handle:</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 13:30:00 +0430</pubDate>
        <link>
        /classes/bec</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/classes/bec</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>IELTS/TOEFL/PTE</title>
        
          <description>Beyond conventional test prep programs
Binesh Afza’s preparation class courses focus on enabling students to understand the content in-depth rather than a download of voluminous basic knowledge interspersed with tricks. Our difference lies in the fact that we care about the students’ literacy as well. Instead of parroting the empty, low-scoring fixed expressions and mechanical constructs, we help you brainstorm and develop your own ideas in your own genuine style. The course also includes a review of grammar and free discussion sessions.
Last but not least, fifty percent of the tuition is refundable if the course fails to help you achieve the band score you need.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 09:30:00 +0430</pubDate>
        <link>
        /classes/IELTS-TOEFL-PTE</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/classes/IELTS-TOEFL-PTE</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Teaching Training Course</title>
        
          <description>TTC prepare students with advanced English Skills for teaching adults or children. Students can choose to teach either Adult Learner (AL) or Young Learner (YL) based on their interest in handling different type of challenges they face for each group.
Binesh Afza Language Institute will issue worldwide recognized TTC certificate under International Labor Organization (ILO) license. This certificate is valid in 187 countries worldwide including but not limited to USA, England, Australia, Canada and most of European countries. TTC certificate can be verified by your potential employer through your TTC certificate international code and the certificate doesn’t need to be translated.
TTC Course will help students to identify: </description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 08:30:00 +0430</pubDate>
        <link>
        /classes/ttc</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/classes/ttc</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>English Podcast</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey! Welcome to Ghost, it’s great to have you :)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 14:30:00 +0430</pubDate>
        <link>
        /news/welcome</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/welcome</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Organising your content with tags</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Ghost has a single, powerful organisational taxonomy, called tags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn't matter whether you want to call them categories, tags, boxes, or anything else. You can think of Ghost tags a lot like Gmail labels. By tagging posts with one or more keyword, you can organise articles into buckets of related content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;basictagging&quot;&gt;Basic tagging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you write a post, you can assign tags to help differentiate between categories of content. For example, you might tag some posts with &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt; and other posts with &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt;, which would create two distinct categories of content listed on &lt;code&gt;/tag/news/&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;/tag/cycling/&lt;/code&gt;, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you tag a post with both &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt; - then it appears in both sections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tag archives are like dedicated home-pages for each category of content that you have. They have their own pages, their own RSS feeds, and can support their own cover images and meta data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;theprimarytag&quot;&gt;The primary tag&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside the Ghost editor, you can drag and drop tags into a specific order. The first tag in the list is always given the most importance, and some themes will only display the primary tag (the first tag in the list) by default. So you can add the most important tag which you want to show up in your theme, but also add a bunch of related tags which are less important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt;, Cycling, Bart Stevens, Extreme Sports&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this example, &lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt; is the primary tag which will be displayed by the theme, but the post will also still receive all the other tags, and show up in their respective archives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;privatetags&quot;&gt;Private tags&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you may want to assign a post a specific tag, but you don't necessarily want that tag appearing in the theme or creating an archive page. In Ghost, hashtags are private and can be used for special styling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if you sometimes publish posts with video content - you might want your theme to adapt and get rid of the sidebar for these posts, to give more space for an embedded video to fill the screen. In this case, you could use private tags to tell your theme what to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt;, Cycling, #video&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, the theme would assign the post publicly displayed tags of &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt; - but it would also keep a private record of the post being tagged with &lt;code&gt;#video&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your theme, you could then look for private tags conditionally and give them special formatting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;nohighlight&quot;&gt;{{#post}}
    {{#has tag=&amp;quot;#video&amp;quot;}}
        ...markup for a nice big video post layout...
    {{else}}
        ...regular markup for a post...
    {{/has}}
{{/post}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find documentation for theme development techniques like this and many more over on Ghost's extensive &lt;a href=&quot;https://themes.ghost.org/&quot;&gt;theme documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 12:30:00 +0430</pubDate>
        <link>
        /news/using-tags</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/using-tags</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Making your site private</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you might want to put your site behind closed doors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've got a publication that you don't want the world to see yet because it's not ready to launch, you can hide your Ghost site behind a simple shared pass-phrase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can toggle this preference on at the bottom of Ghost's General Settings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://casper.ghost.org/v1.0.0/images/private.png&quot; alt=&quot;private&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ghost will give you a short, randomly generated pass-phrase which you can share with anyone who needs access to the site while you're working on it. While this setting is enabled, all search engine optimisation features will be switched off to help keep the site off the radar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do remember though, this is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; secure authentication. You shouldn't rely on this feature for protecting important private data. It's just a simple, shared pass-phrase for very basic privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 10:30:00 +0430</pubDate>
        <link>
        /news/private-sites</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/private-sites</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>A Full and Comprehensive Style Test</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Below is just about everything you’ll need to style in the theme. Check the source code to see the many embedded elements within paragraphs.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 14:30:00 +0430</pubDate>
        <link>
        /blog/a-full-and-comprehensive-style-test</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/a-full-and-comprehensive-style-test</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Out to Sea</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I had this story from one who had no business to tell it to me, or to any other. I may credit the seductive influence of an old vintage upon the narrator for the beginning of it, and my own skeptical incredulity during the days that followed for the balance of the strange tale.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 1912 13:45:12 +0325</pubDate>
        <link>
        /blog/out-to-sea</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/out-to-sea</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Looking-Glass house</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;One thing was certain, that the white kitten had had nothing to do with it:— it was the black kitten’s fault entirely. For the white kitten had been having its face washed by the old cat for the last quarter of an hour (and bearing it pretty well, considering); so you see that it couldn’t have had any hand in the mischief.
The way Dinah washed her children’s faces was this: first she held the poor thing down by its ear with one paw, and then with the other paw she rubbed its face all over, the wrong way, beginning at the nose: and just now, as I said, she was hard at work on the white kitten, which was lying quite still and trying to purr — no doubt feeling that it was all meant for its good.
But the black kitten had been finished with earlier in the afternoon, and so, while Alice was sitting curled up in a corner of the great arm-chair, half talking to herself and half asleep, the kitten had been having a grand game of romps with the ball of worsted Alice had been trying to wind up, and had been rolling it up and down till it had all come undone again; and there it was, spread over the hearth-rug, all knots and tangles, with the kitten running after its own tail in the middle.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 1871 13:45:12 +0325</pubDate>
        <link>
        /blog/looking-glass-house</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/looking-glass-house</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Down The Rabbit Hole</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Alice was beginning to get very tired of sitting by her sister on the bank, and of having nothing to do: once or twice she had peeped into the book her sister was reading, but it had no pictures or conversations in it, ‘and what is the use of a book,’ thought Alice ‘without pictures or conversation?’&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 1865 13:45:12 +0325</pubDate>
        <link>
        /blog/down-the-rabbit-hole</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/down-the-rabbit-hole</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Gettysburg Address</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Fourscore and seven years ago our fathers brought forth on this continent, a new nation, conceived in Liberty, and dedicated to the proposition that all men are created equal.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 1863 13:45:12 +0325</pubDate>
        <link>
        /blog/gettysburg-address</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/gettysburg-address</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
