<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="/en/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/en/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-12-16T02:29:16+03:30</updated><id>/en/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Binesh Afza</title><subtitle>Think like a native, Speak like a native.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">IELTS Speaking Tip 2</title><link href="/en/blog/IELTS-Speaking-Tip-2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IELTS Speaking Tip 2" /><published>2018-11-23T17:14:48+03:30</published><updated>2018-11-23T17:14:48+03:30</updated><id>/en/blog/IELTS-Speaking-Tip-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="/en/blog/IELTS-Speaking-Tip-2">&lt;h1 id=&quot;ielts-speaking-tip-2&quot;&gt;IELTS Speaking Tip 2&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;part-2&quot;&gt;PART 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the second part of the speaking test, candidates are supposed to talk about a cue card/ task card for one to two minutes. As intimidating as it may sound (talking for two minutes), it can be made easy if candidates learn how to adopt appropriate strategies to extend their answers. Well, good news is, today we’re going to learn a British Council approved strategy which can come in handy if you don’t know how to get things going in part2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-strategy-is-called-ppf-read-the-task-card-below-and-then-read-my-notes&quot;&gt;The strategy is called PPF! Read the task card below and then read my notes.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you think PPF stands for?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;P :  “It was definitely far more exciting than any other TV series I’d watched before. I’d only followed some dramas so Rick &amp;amp; Morty was a completely different experience for me, it features only three to four main characters….”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;P : “I’ve got some screenshots from the series on my computer. They come up as screensavers after my computer hasn’t been used for a while, so I look at them and start thinking about its mind-boggling plot and every time I feel the urge to watch it again, this time maybe with friends.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;F : “Actually, I’m planning to make my girlfriend watch it with me, but the thing is, I’m not sure if she finds it as interesting because she’s so serious and can’t easily relate to its dirty jokes. We’ll probably just watch a couple of episodes to see how things turns out, I can’t wait!….”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOW THINK ABOUT A TV SERIES THAT YOU ENJOYED WATCHING AND MAKE SOME NOTES ABOUT WHAT YOU COULD SAY (PPF)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PAST:                        ——————————————————————-.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PRESENT:               ——————————————————————-.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FUTURE:                ——————————————————————-.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YOU CAN RECORD YOUR VOICE AND SEND IT TO OUR &lt;a href=&quot;mailto: info@bineshafza.ir&quot;&gt;EMAIL ADDRESS&lt;/a&gt; TO GET FEEDBACK.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Omid Roshandel</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="IELTS" /><category term="Speaking" /><category term="Tips" /><summary type="html">IELTS Speaking Tip 2</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IELTS Speaking Tip 1</title><link href="/en/blog/IELTS-Speaking-Tip-1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IELTS Speaking Tip 1" /><published>2018-11-17T16:56:28+03:30</published><updated>2018-11-17T16:56:28+03:30</updated><id>/en/blog/IELTS-Speaking-Tip-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="/en/blog/IELTS-Speaking-Tip-1">&lt;h1 id=&quot;ielts-speaking-tip-1&quot;&gt;IELTS SPEAKING TIP #1&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;part-1&quot;&gt;Part 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three parts to the IELTS speaking test (DUH!). In the first part of the test the examiner asks you some personal questions (e.g. what’s your favorite color?). The problem is, sometimes candidates get confused because their real answer to some of these questions is “NO”, but because at some point in their life someone pulled her/his lips apart from theirs and looked them in the eye and said-in a low, celestial voice- “DO NOT GIVE SHORT ANSWERS”, they assume “NO” in the IELTS speaking test, like smoking in everyday life, KILLS. Good news is, unlike smoking, saying “NO” actually can get you out of trouble in part 1. Even if you’re an accomplished liar and can think of minor details to include in your imaginary plot, you’d be better off telling the truth!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-say-no-in-part-1-and-feel-good-about-it&quot;&gt;HOW TO SAY NO IN PART 1 AND FEEL GOOD ABOUT IT!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no doubt that saying NO is not enough on the IELTS test, because that’ll be too short to allow the examiner to assess your language skills. So what should we do?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is fairly simple. All you have to do is explain why you think the answer is NO. You can give some relevant details, or make some examples, or do virtually anything else that can help support your answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the question and the answer below to get a better understanding of how telling the truth (NO) can help you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;   Do you often watch TV?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Erm…actually I should say no, not at all. It’s been five years now that I haven’t watched TV for even a single second. I prefer reading, and it’ll come extremely out of character for me to watch TV. When I was a child though, I used to watch cartoons on TV, but the thing is as I grew up, I began to realize TV programs are nothing but boring, and they make me sick to stomach! And that’s all there is to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;its-your-turn-now&quot;&gt;IT’S YOUR TURN NOW!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the following question and feel free to say NO! record your voice and send it to me to get feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Has television changed your life in any way?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’m gonna say NO…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please click on the link below to upload your voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/forms/QVnmbAO3JXnXKrSJ3&quot;&gt;Upload File&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Omid Roshandel</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="IELTS" /><category term="Speaking" /><category term="Tips" /><summary type="html">IELTS SPEAKING TIP #1</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Toastmasters</title><link href="/en/classes/Toastmasters" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Toastmasters" /><published>2018-11-01T03:30:00+03:30</published><updated>2018-11-01T03:30:00+03:30</updated><id>/en/classes/Toastmasters</id><content type="html" xml:base="/en/classes/Toastmasters">&lt;p&gt;Our Toastmasters Classes are starting from next Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this course we are going to cover “How to inform” and “ How to tell a story”. We are going to discuss the different techniques and styles necessary for each type of speech.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bineshafza</name></author><category term="classes" /><summary type="html">Our Toastmasters Classes are starting from next Sunday. In this course we are going to cover “How to inform” and “ How to tell a story”. We are going to discuss the different techniques and styles necessary for each type of speech.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Writing Essay (Part 2)</title><link href="/en/blog/IELTS-Essay-2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Writing Essay (Part 2)" /><published>2018-10-09T13:48:00+03:30</published><updated>2018-10-09T13:48:00+03:30</updated><id>/en/blog/IELTS-Essay-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="/en/blog/IELTS-Essay-2">&lt;p&gt;When facing a writing task, there are five possible forms of questions. We’ll help you have an idea of what to do with the question. These are the five types:
Opinion Essay Questions
 Discussion Essay Questions
Solution Essay Questions
Direct Questions Essay Titles
Advantage/ Disadvantage Essay Question
Each of them will be explained one by one in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bahram Hossein</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="IELTS" /><category term="Writing" /><summary type="html">When facing a writing task, there are five possible forms of questions. We’ll help you have an idea of what to do with the question. These are the five types: Opinion Essay Questions Discussion Essay Questions Solution Essay Questions Direct Questions Essay Titles Advantage/ Disadvantage Essay Question Each of them will be explained one by one in the coming weeks.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Writing Essay</title><link href="/en/blog/IELTS-Essay" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Writing Essay" /><published>2018-10-08T13:48:00+03:30</published><updated>2018-10-08T13:48:00+03:30</updated><id>/en/blog/IELTS-Essay</id><content type="html" xml:base="/en/blog/IELTS-Essay">&lt;p&gt;For writing a good essay, there are many steps you need to take. But before taking those steps you need to be informed on the topics. The most frequent topics are:
Art&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Business &amp;amp; Money&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communication &amp;amp; Personality&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crime &amp;amp; Punishment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Education&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Environment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Family &amp;amp; Children&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food &amp;amp; Diet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Government&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Health&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Housing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Language&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leisure&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Media &amp;amp; Advertising&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Society&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Space Exploration&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sport &amp;amp; Exercise&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tourism&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Transport&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So before starting a writing course, try to expose yourself to texts and videos on these topics so you always know what’s needed.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bahram Hossein</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="IELTS" /><category term="Writing" /><summary type="html">For writing a good essay, there are many steps you need to take. But before taking those steps you need to be informed on the topics. The most frequent topics are: Art</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">EPT/MSRT Preparation Course</title><link href="/en/classes/EPT-MSRT" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EPT/MSRT Preparation Course" /><published>2018-08-12T14:48:00+04:30</published><updated>2018-08-12T14:48:00+04:30</updated><id>/en/classes/EPT-MSRT</id><content type="html" xml:base="/en/classes/EPT-MSRT">&lt;p&gt;EPT (English Proficiency Test) is launched by Islamic Azad University (IAU) for PhD test takers to examine their proficiency in English language. The exam including 25 questions on vocabulary, 40 questions on grammatical points and 35 questions on comprehensive reading. The exam doesn’t have negative scores and exam pass score is 50% of total score.
Research and development center of IAU noted following text books as reference for this exam:&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bineshafza</name></author><category term="classes" /><category term="Exam" /><summary type="html">EPT (English Proficiency Test) is launched by Islamic Azad University (IAU) for PhD test takers to examine their proficiency in English language. The exam including 25 questions on vocabulary, 40 questions on grammatical points and 35 questions on comprehensive reading. The exam doesn’t have negative scores and exam pass score is 50% of total score. Research and development center of IAU noted following text books as reference for this exam:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Business English Course</title><link href="/en/classes/BEC" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Business English Course" /><published>2018-07-27T13:30:00+04:30</published><updated>2018-07-27T13:30:00+04:30</updated><id>/en/classes/BEC</id><content type="html" xml:base="/en/classes/BEC">BEC is a well-recognized international certificate that launched by Cambridge English. The aim of test is to examine English Skills in a business context.
There are three levels of BEC:
1- BEC Preliminary (B1): to understand routine letters, make notes, follow basic presentations and advise clients on simple matters. (Prerequisite: Intermediate level of Professional trade language Course)
2- BEC Vantage (B2): to understand the general meaning of reports, write non-routine letters and present arguments. (Prerequisite: Upper-Intermediate level of Professional trade language Course)
3- BEC Higher (C1): to deal with unpredictable questions, argue a business case and write business reports. (Prerequisite: Advanced level of Professional trade language Course)
This is a lifetime certificate that can boost your opportunities in international corporations. More corporates and Businesses require their employees to hold BEC certificate before they are recruited. Sony, Shell, Vodafone, Bayer, BMW, AUDI, HSBC, Adidas are only a few companies to mention in growing list of corporates that require their employees to hold BEC certificate.
Binesh Afza Language Institute’s Professional Trade Language Course can help not only professional business man/woman handling their challenging situations in business but also can help you prepare for BEC Exam. Students and Professors of International Trading Courses, Organization legal department representatives, business owners and people who are offering business advice to international corporates can be benefited greatly from this course.
You are expected to have an intermediate level of knowledge in English language skills before Professional Trade Language Course at Binesh Afza Language Institute. This course will enable you to professionally handle:</content><author><name>Bineshafza</name></author><category term="classes" /><category term="Getting started" /><summary type="html">BEC is a well-recognized international certificate that launched by Cambridge English. The aim of test is to examine English Skills in a business context. There are three levels of BEC: 1- BEC Preliminary (B1): to understand routine letters, make notes, follow basic presentations and advise clients on simple matters. (Prerequisite: Intermediate level of Professional trade language Course) 2- BEC Vantage (B2): to understand the general meaning of reports, write non-routine letters and present arguments. (Prerequisite: Upper-Intermediate level of Professional trade language Course) 3- BEC Higher (C1): to deal with unpredictable questions, argue a business case and write business reports. (Prerequisite: Advanced level of Professional trade language Course) This is a lifetime certificate that can boost your opportunities in international corporations. More corporates and Businesses require their employees to hold BEC certificate before they are recruited. Sony, Shell, Vodafone, Bayer, BMW, AUDI, HSBC, Adidas are only a few companies to mention in growing list of corporates that require their employees to hold BEC certificate. Binesh Afza Language Institute’s Professional Trade Language Course can help not only professional business man/woman handling their challenging situations in business but also can help you prepare for BEC Exam. Students and Professors of International Trading Courses, Organization legal department representatives, business owners and people who are offering business advice to international corporates can be benefited greatly from this course. You are expected to have an intermediate level of knowledge in English language skills before Professional Trade Language Course at Binesh Afza Language Institute. This course will enable you to professionally handle:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IELTS/TOEFL/PTE</title><link href="/en/classes/IELTS-TOEFL-PTE" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IELTS/TOEFL/PTE" /><published>2018-07-27T09:30:00+04:30</published><updated>2018-07-27T09:30:00+04:30</updated><id>/en/classes/IELTS-TOEFL-PTE</id><content type="html" xml:base="/en/classes/IELTS-TOEFL-PTE">Beyond conventional test prep programs
Binesh Afza’s preparation class courses focus on enabling students to understand the content in-depth rather than a download of voluminous basic knowledge interspersed with tricks. Our difference lies in the fact that we care about the students’ literacy as well. Instead of parroting the empty, low-scoring fixed expressions and mechanical constructs, we help you brainstorm and develop your own ideas in your own genuine style. The course also includes a review of grammar and free discussion sessions.
Last but not least, fifty percent of the tuition is refundable if the course fails to help you achieve the band score you need.</content><author><name>Bineshafza</name></author><category term="classes" /><category term="Getting started" /><summary type="html">Beyond conventional test prep programs Binesh Afza’s preparation class courses focus on enabling students to understand the content in-depth rather than a download of voluminous basic knowledge interspersed with tricks. Our difference lies in the fact that we care about the students’ literacy as well. Instead of parroting the empty, low-scoring fixed expressions and mechanical constructs, we help you brainstorm and develop your own ideas in your own genuine style. The course also includes a review of grammar and free discussion sessions. Last but not least, fifty percent of the tuition is refundable if the course fails to help you achieve the band score you need.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Teaching Training Course</title><link href="/en/classes/TTC" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Teaching Training Course" /><published>2018-07-27T08:30:00+04:30</published><updated>2018-07-27T08:30:00+04:30</updated><id>/en/classes/TTC</id><content type="html" xml:base="/en/classes/TTC">TTC prepare students with advanced English Skills for teaching adults or children. Students can choose to teach either Adult Learner (AL) or Young Learner (YL) based on their interest in handling different type of challenges they face for each group.
Binesh Afza Language Institute will issue worldwide recognized TTC certificate under International Labor Organization (ILO) license. This certificate is valid in 187 countries worldwide including but not limited to USA, England, Australia, Canada and most of European countries. TTC certificate can be verified by your potential employer through your TTC certificate international code and the certificate doesn’t need to be translated.
TTC Course will help students to identify:</content><author><name>Bineshafza</name></author><category term="classes" /><category term="Getting started" /><summary type="html">TTC prepare students with advanced English Skills for teaching adults or children. Students can choose to teach either Adult Learner (AL) or Young Learner (YL) based on their interest in handling different type of challenges they face for each group. Binesh Afza Language Institute will issue worldwide recognized TTC certificate under International Labor Organization (ILO) license. This certificate is valid in 187 countries worldwide including but not limited to USA, England, Australia, Canada and most of European countries. TTC certificate can be verified by your potential employer through your TTC certificate international code and the certificate doesn’t need to be translated. TTC Course will help students to identify:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">English Podcast</title><link href="/en/news/Welcome" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="English Podcast" /><published>2017-07-27T14:30:00+04:30</published><updated>2017-07-27T14:30:00+04:30</updated><id>/en/news/Welcome</id><content type="html" xml:base="/en/news/Welcome">&lt;p&gt;Hey! Welcome to Ghost, it’s great to have you :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know that first impressions are important, so we’ve populated your new site with some initial &lt;strong&gt;Getting Started&lt;/strong&gt; posts that will help you get familiar with everything in no time. This is the first one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;there-are-a-few-things-that-you-should-know-up-front&quot;&gt;There are a few things that you should know up-front:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ghost is designed for ambitious, professional publishers who want to actively build a business around their content. That’s who it works best for. If you’re using Ghost for some other purpose, that’s fine too - but it might not be the best choice for you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The entire platform can be modified and customized to suit your needs, which is very powerful, but doing so &lt;strong&gt;does&lt;/strong&gt; require some knowledge of code. Ghost is not necessarily a good platform for beginners or people who just want a simple personal blog.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For the best experience we recommend downloading the Ghost Desktop App for your computer, which is the best way to access your Ghost site on a desktop device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ghost is made by an independent non-profit organisation called the Ghost Foundation. We are 100% self funded by revenue from our &lt;a href=&quot;https://ghost.org/pricing&quot;&gt;Ghost(Pro)&lt;/a&gt; service, and every penny we make is re-invested into funding further development of free, open source technology for modern journalism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main thing you’ll want to read about next is probably: &lt;a href=&quot;https://demo.ghost.io/the-editor/&quot;&gt;the Ghost editor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’re done reading, you can simply delete the default &lt;strong&gt;Ghost&lt;/strong&gt; user from your team to remove all of these introductory posts!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bineshafza</name></author><category term="news" /><category term="Getting started" /><summary type="html">Hey! Welcome to Ghost, it’s great to have you :) We know that first impressions are important, so we’ve populated your new site with some initial Getting Started posts that will help you get familiar with everything in no time. This is the first one! There are a few things that you should know up-front: Ghost is designed for ambitious, professional publishers who want to actively build a business around their content. That’s who it works best for. If you’re using Ghost for some other purpose, that’s fine too - but it might not be the best choice for you. The entire platform can be modified and customized to suit your needs, which is very powerful, but doing so does require some knowledge of code. Ghost is not necessarily a good platform for beginners or people who just want a simple personal blog. For the best experience we recommend downloading the Ghost Desktop App for your computer, which is the best way to access your Ghost site on a desktop device. Ghost is made by an independent non-profit organisation called the Ghost Foundation. We are 100% self funded by revenue from our Ghost(Pro) service, and every penny we make is re-invested into funding further development of free, open source technology for modern journalism. The main thing you’ll want to read about next is probably: the Ghost editor. Once you’re done reading, you can simply delete the default Ghost user from your team to remove all of these introductory posts!</summary></entry></feed>