<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="/en/tag/tips/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/en/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2018-11-27T02:25:07+03:30</updated>
  <id>/en/tag/tips/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Binesh Afza | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Think like a native, Speak like a native.</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">IELTS Speaking Tip 2</title>
      <link href="/en/blog/ielts-speaking-tip-2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IELTS Speaking Tip 2" />
      <published>2018-11-23T17:14:48+03:30</published>
      <updated>2018-11-23T17:14:48+03:30</updated>
      <id>/en/blog/ielts-speaking-tip-2</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/en/blog/ielts-speaking-tip-2">&lt;h1 id=&quot;ielts-speaking-tip-2&quot;&gt;IELTS Speaking Tip 2&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;part-2&quot;&gt;PART 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the second part of the speaking test, candidates are supposed to talk about a cue card/ task card for one to two minutes. As intimidating as it may sound (talking for two minutes), it can be made easy if candidates learn how to adopt appropriate strategies to extend their answers. Well, good news is, today we’re going to learn a British Council approved strategy which can come in handy if you don’t know how to get things going in part2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-strategy-is-called-ppf-read-the-task-card-below-and-then-read-my-notes&quot;&gt;The strategy is called PPF! Read the task card below and then read my notes.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you think PPF stands for?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;P :  “It was definitely far more exciting than any other TV series I’d watched before. I’d only followed some dramas so Rick &amp;amp; Morty was a completely different experience for me, it features only three to four main characters….”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;P : “I’ve got some screenshots from the series on my computer. They come up as screensavers after my computer hasn’t been used for a while, so I look at them and start thinking about its mind-boggling plot and every time I feel the urge to watch it again, this time maybe with friends.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;F : “Actually, I’m planning to make my girlfriend watch it with me, but the thing is, I’m not sure if she finds it as interesting because she’s so serious and can’t easily relate to its dirty jokes. We’ll probably just watch a couple of episodes to see how things turns out, I can’t wait!….”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOW THINK ABOUT A TV SERIES THAT YOU ENJOYED WATCHING AND MAKE SOME NOTES ABOUT WHAT YOU COULD SAY (PPF)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PAST:                        —————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PRESENT:               —————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————–.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FUTURE:                —————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————–.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YOU CAN RECORD YOUR VOICE AND SEND IT TO OUR &lt;a href=&quot;mailto: info@bineshafza.ir&quot;&gt;Email address&lt;/a&gt; TO GET FEEDBACK.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Omid Roshandel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      
        <category term="blog" />
      

      
        <category term="IELTS" />
      
        <category term="Speaking" />
      
        <category term="Tips" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">IELTS Speaking Tip 2</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
