<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="/en/tag/tips/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/en/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2019-01-01T18:43:38+03:30</updated>
  <id>/en/tag/tips/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Binesh Afza | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Think like a native, Speak like a native</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">IELTS Speaking Tip 2</title>
      <link href="/en/blog/IELTS-Speaking-Tip-2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IELTS Speaking Tip 2" />
      <published>2018-11-23T17:14:48+03:30</published>
      <updated>2018-11-23T17:14:48+03:30</updated>
      <id>/en/blog/IELTS-Speaking-Tip-2</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/en/blog/IELTS-Speaking-Tip-2">&lt;h1 id=&quot;ielts-speaking-tip-2&quot;&gt;IELTS Speaking Tip 2&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;part-2&quot;&gt;PART 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the second part of the speaking test, candidates are supposed to talk about a cue card/ task card for one to two minutes. As intimidating as it may sound (talking for two minutes), it can be made easy if candidates learn how to adopt appropriate strategies to extend their answers. Well, good news is, today we’re going to learn a British Council approved strategy which can come in handy if you don’t know how to get things going in part2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-strategy-is-called-ppf-read-the-task-card-below-and-then-read-my-notes&quot;&gt;The strategy is called PPF! Read the task card below and then read my notes.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you think PPF stands for?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;P :  “It was definitely far more exciting than any other TV series I’d watched before. I’d only followed some dramas so Rick &amp;amp; Morty was a completely different experience for me, it features only three to four main characters….”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;P : “I’ve got some screenshots from the series on my computer. They come up as screensavers after my computer hasn’t been used for a while, so I look at them and start thinking about its mind-boggling plot and every time I feel the urge to watch it again, this time maybe with friends.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;F : “Actually, I’m planning to make my girlfriend watch it with me, but the thing is, I’m not sure if she finds it as interesting because she’s so serious and can’t easily relate to its dirty jokes. We’ll probably just watch a couple of episodes to see how things turns out, I can’t wait!….”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOW THINK ABOUT A TV SERIES THAT YOU ENJOYED WATCHING AND MAKE SOME NOTES ABOUT WHAT YOU COULD SAY (PPF)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PAST:                        ——————————————————————-.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PRESENT:               ——————————————————————-.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FUTURE:                ——————————————————————-.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YOU CAN RECORD YOUR VOICE AND SEND IT TO OUR &lt;a href=&quot;mailto: info@bineshafza.ir&quot;&gt;EMAIL ADDRESS&lt;/a&gt; TO GET FEEDBACK.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Omid Roshandel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      
        <category term="blog" />
      

      
        <category term="IELTS" />
      
        <category term="Speaking" />
      
        <category term="Tips" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">IELTS Speaking Tip 2</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">IELTS Speaking Tip 1</title>
      <link href="/en/blog/IELTS-Speaking-Tip-1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IELTS Speaking Tip 1" />
      <published>2018-11-17T16:56:28+03:30</published>
      <updated>2018-11-17T16:56:28+03:30</updated>
      <id>/en/blog/IELTS-Speaking-Tip-1</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/en/blog/IELTS-Speaking-Tip-1">&lt;h1 id=&quot;ielts-speaking-tip-1&quot;&gt;IELTS SPEAKING TIP #1&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;part-1&quot;&gt;Part 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three parts to the IELTS speaking test (DUH!). In the first part of the test the examiner asks you some personal questions (e.g. what’s your favorite color?). The problem is, sometimes candidates get confused because their real answer to some of these questions is “NO”, but because at some point in their life someone pulled her/his lips apart from theirs and looked them in the eye and said-in a low, celestial voice- “DO NOT GIVE SHORT ANSWERS”, they assume “NO” in the IELTS speaking test, like smoking in everyday life, KILLS. Good news is, unlike smoking, saying “NO” actually can get you out of trouble in part 1. Even if you’re an accomplished liar and can think of minor details to include in your imaginary plot, you’d be better off telling the truth!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-say-no-in-part-1-and-feel-good-about-it&quot;&gt;HOW TO SAY NO IN PART 1 AND FEEL GOOD ABOUT IT!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no doubt that saying NO is not enough on the IELTS test, because that’ll be too short to allow the examiner to assess your language skills. So what should we do?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is fairly simple. All you have to do is explain why you think the answer is NO. You can give some relevant details, or make some examples, or do virtually anything else that can help support your answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the question and the answer below to get a better understanding of how telling the truth (NO) can help you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;   Do you often watch TV?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Erm…actually I should say no, not at all. It’s been five years now that I haven’t watched TV for even a single second. I prefer reading, and it’ll come extremely out of character for me to watch TV. When I was a child though, I used to watch cartoons on TV, but the thing is as I grew up, I began to realize TV programs are nothing but boring, and they make me sick to stomach! And that’s all there is to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;its-your-turn-now&quot;&gt;IT’S YOUR TURN NOW!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the following question and feel free to say NO! record your voice and send it to me to get feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Has television changed your life in any way?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’m gonna say NO…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please click on the link below to upload your voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/forms/QVnmbAO3JXnXKrSJ3&quot;&gt;Upload File&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Omid Roshandel</name>
        
        
      </author>

      
        <category term="blog" />
      

      
        <category term="IELTS" />
      
        <category term="Speaking" />
      
        <category term="Tips" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">IELTS SPEAKING TIP #1</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
